// flashcards/atc.js
export const atc = [
      { front : `What is a TMU? Where are they located?`, back: `Traffic Management Unit. Located in ARTCCs (and some TRACONs)` },
      { front : `What do TMUs issue?`, back: `They issue ground stops and ground delay programs` },
      { front : `What are the 2 types of radar ATC uses?`, back: `Primary and secondary` },
      { front : `What does a Clearance Delivery controller provide to a flightcrew?`, back: `<ul><li>Clearance limit (usually the destination)</li>
<li>Route of flight</li>
<li>Transponder code</li></ul>` },
      { front : `What is TRACON?`, back: `Terminal Radar Approach Control` },
      { front : `What does a TRACON provide?`, back: `It provides approach and departure control services for an aircraft entering and exiting terminal areas` },
      { front : `What is TMI?`, back: `Traffic Management Initiatives` },
      { front : `Ground stops and ground delays are issued by who?`, back: `Traffic Management Units (TMU) at the ARTCC (or some TRACONs)` },
      { front : `What does primary radar provide to ATC?`, back: `Aircraft position` },
      { front : `How early can you file a flight plan with ATC?`, back: `30 minutes` },
      { front : `What is ASDE?`, back: `Airport Surface Detection Equipment` },
      { front : `What does ASDE provide ATC?`, back: `The ability to track an aircraft on the ground via the aircrafts transponder` },
      { front : `What does secondary radar provide to ATC?`, back: `Thansponder information, ex; position, altitude, and call sign` },
      { front : `Is an average heading of 360degrees considered eastbound or westbound?`, back: `Eastbound` },
      { front : `What are the 3 non-discreet transponder codes?`, back: `7500 - Hijacking
7600 - Loss of radio communications
7700 - All other emergencies` },
      { front : `What does the Tower controller provide to the flight crew?`, back: `Takeoff and landing clearance` },
      { front : `What are the requirements when crossing and ADIZ over water?`, back: `To cross within 5 minutes and 20 NM of where you planned/stated your intention to cross` },
      { front : `What are the universal emergency radio frequencies?`, back: `VHF: 121.5<br>
UHF: 243` },
      { front : `What is an ADIZ? What does it provide?`, back: `Air Defense Identificaition Zone. It's an airspace over land or water, within which the identification, location, and control of civil aircraft is performed in the interest of national security` },
      { front : `How long after ETD does ATC clearance expire?`, back: `2 Hours` },
      { front : `How long before ETD does ATC provide clearance for departure?`, back: `10 Minutes` },
      { front : `How does ATC identify a spcific aircraft via its transponder?`, back: `By issuing a four-digit "squawk" code unique to that aircraft, to which the pilot(s) set their transponder(s)` },
      { front : `Are westbound flights planned to cruise at odd- or even-numbered flight levels?`, back: `Even-numbered` },
      { front : `What is a LAHSO?`, back: `Land and Hold Short Operations` },
      { front : `How does LAHSO work?`, back: `A point in which an aircraft landing must come to a complete stop (during specific hours), generally before the intersection of 2 runways` },
];
